export const chapter =
  "Chapter - 3: Expansion of Colonial Administration and Army ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Why did the East India Company's strategy shift from indirect measures to direct attacks on Indian states?",
        optionA: "To increase diplomatic relations",
        optionB: "To expand its territory",
        optionC: "To promote trade with Indian rulers",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Indian ruler suffered a massive defeat at the hands of Nadir Shah in 1739?",
        optionA: "Hyder Ali",
        optionB: "Tipu Sultan",
        optionC: "Mughals",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which policy did the Company start after occupying Bengal and continued from 1757 to 1856?",
        optionA: "Doctrine of Lapse",
        optionB: "Subsidiary Alliance",
        optionC: "Direct Attack",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Under the Subsidiary Alliance System, what did Indian rulers have to do with a British army on their territory?",
        optionA: "Command the army",
        optionB: "Pay for the army's upkeep",
        optionC: "Train the army",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who was the first Indian ruler to enter into the Subsidiary Alliance System in 1798?",
        optionA: "Tipu Sultan",
        optionB: "Nizam of Hyderabad",
        optionC: "Nawab of Awadh",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question: "What was the result of the Fourth Anglo-Mysore War in 1799?",
        optionA:
          "The British defeated Tipu Sultan, and Mysore became part of the Company's territory.",
        optionB:
          "Tipu Sultan defeated the British, and the Company withdrew from Mysore.",
        optionC:
          "A peace treaty was signed, allowing both parties to maintain their territories.",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Maratha ruler established a confederacy of Maratha chiefs, hoping to strengthen the Maratha empire?",
        optionA: "Shivaji",
        optionB: "Baji Rao II",
        optionC: "Madhav Rao II",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What policy did the British force on the Marathas in the Second Anglo-Maratha War?",
        optionA: "Subsidiary Alliance",
        optionB: "Doctrine of Lapse",
        optionC: "Direct Attack",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the main cause of the Maratha decline against the British?",
        optionA: "Lack of bravery",
        optionB: "Lack of military technology advancement",
        optionC: "Lack of unity among Maratha chiefs",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What policy did Lord Dalhousie devise in 1848 to annex more states, including Awadh in 1856?",
        optionA: "Subsidiary Alliance",
        optionB: "Doctrine of Lapse",
        optionC: "Direct Attack",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The East India Company occupied Bengal after taking a variety of __________ measures to exploit the Indian rulers.",
        optionA: "political",
        optionB: "diplomatic",
        optionC: "economic",
        correctAnswer: "political",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The defeat of the later Mughals at the hands of Nadir Shah in 1739 left them in a state of __________.",
        optionA: "prosperity",
        optionB: "pity",
        optionC: "power",
        correctAnswer: "pity",
      },
      {
        question:
          "After the occupation of Bengal, the East India Company started using direct attacks as an important part of its strategy to expand its territory from 1757 to 1856, beginning with the state of __________.",
        optionA: "Mysore",
        optionB: "Awadh",
        optionC: "Marathas",
        correctAnswer: "Mysore",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Indian rulers who agreed to the Subsidiary Alliance System had to maintain a British army on their territory under British __________.",
        optionA: "command",
        optionB: "control",
        optionC: "support",
        correctAnswer: "control",
      },
      {
        question:
          "An Indian ruler was given protection from external attacks, but he could not enter into an alliance with any other power, nor could he attack or seek peace with any other power, making him fully __________ on the British.",
        optionA: "independent",
        optionB: "reliant",
        optionC: "dependent",
        correctAnswer: "dependent",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The First Anglo-Mysore War in 1766-67 ended inconclusively, with a treaty signed that required the Company to help Mysore in case of any __________ against it.",
        optionA: "aggression",
        optionB: "defeat",
        optionC: "diplomacy",
        correctAnswer: "aggression",
      },
      {
        question:
          "During the Third Anglo-Mysore War (1790-92), Tipu Sultan aimed to establish friendly relations with the French and expand his territory in an effort to free India from __________.",
        optionA: "British",
        optionB: "poverty",
        optionC: "control",
        correctAnswer: "British",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British attacked Mysore with the help of the Nizam of Hyderabad and the Marathas in the Fourth Anglo-Mysore War in 1799, resulting in the death of Tipu Sultan and the British occupation of a large part of the state of Mysore, while the old Wodeyar dynasty was reinstated on the __________ territories.",
        optionA: "remaining",
        optionB: "expanded",
        optionC: "conquered",
        correctAnswer: "remaining",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the Third Anglo-Maratha War (1817-18), the Maratha chiefs fought separately rather than standing united, which led to their conclusive defeat, the deposition of the Peshwa, and the annexation of all his territories by the __________.",
        optionA: "Marathas",
        optionB: "British",
        optionC: "French",
        correctAnswer: "British",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British claimed that their authority was paramount or supreme in India, allowing them to annex any territory or state if their interests were harmed, thus solidifying their position as the __________ masters of the most part of present-day India.",
        optionA: "powerful",
        optionB: "unquestionable",
        optionC: "inferior",
        correctAnswer: "unquestionable",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The East India Company occupied Bengal after taking a variety of measures to exploit the Indian rulers.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The defeat of the later Mughals at the hands of Nadir Shah in 1739 left them in a state of prosperity.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "After the occupation of Bengal, the East India Company started using direct attacks as an important part of its strategy to expand its territory from 1757 to 1856, beginning with the state of Mysore.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Indian rulers who agreed to the Subsidiary Alliance System had full control over the British army stationed in their territories.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "An Indian ruler was given protection from external attacks and had the freedom to enter into alliances with any other power.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The First Anglo-Mysore War in 1766-67 concluded with a clear victory for the East India Company.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Tipu Sultan aimed to establish friendly relations with the British during the Third Anglo-Mysore War.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British attacked Mysore with the help of the Nizam of Hyderabad and the Marathas in the Fourth Anglo-Mysore War, leading to the defeat of Tipu Sultan and the British occupation of the entire state.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the Third Anglo-Maratha War, the Maratha chiefs fought unitedly against the British.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British claimed that their authority was not paramount in India, and they had no power to annex territories or states.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
